ponoko.com 2014-11-22

# Copyright and intellectual property - Legal Stuff - Ponoko

## Privacy policy

This privacy statement covers all aspects of the Ponoko website. Please read it carefully before accessing the site.

### Information collection

Ponoko is the sole owner of the information collected on the site. We may collect information from our users at several different points on the site.

Ponoko takes all necessary precautions to ensure that the personal information of our users, including credit card information, is kept confidential. Your credit card information is protected during transmission over the internet by encryption using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) prototcol. Such credit card information is not held by us but may be held by [Direct Payment Solutions (DPS)](http://www.paymentexpress.com/about/about_paymentexpress/privacy_policy.html "DPS Privacy Policy") or [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/us/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=p/gen/ua/policy_privacy-outside "PayPal Privacy Policy") depending on which payment provider processes the transaction. 

### Comments

In order to enhance your use of Ponoko, you can choose to leave comments on particular areas of interest. To leave a comment, you need to submit information including a valid email address. We use this information to screen out users who leave comments prohibited by our terms of use. We will not pass this information to any other organization.

### Mailing list

Ponoko may launch a mailing list for some or all of the site. In order to sign up to receive regular emails from a mailing list, you need to submit information including a valid email address and demographic information such as location and interests. We will only use this information in aggregate form in order to assess general user interest in various internal and third-party products and services. We will not pass your personal and contact information to any other organization. You will receive regular emails from the site if you choose to sign up for a mailing list.

### Log files

Like many standard website servers, we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the site, track users' movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. We may use a tracking utility that uses log files to analyze user movement.

### Legal disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, Ponoko may need to disclose personal information when required by law where we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on Ponoko.

### Business transitions

In the event Ponoko goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of a portion of its assets, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred.

### Links

Our website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Ponoko is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by Ponoko.

### Notification of changes

Whenever Ponoko changes its privacy policy, we will post those changes here, and other places we think appropriate so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

### Contact information

If you have any questions or suggestions about our privacy policy, please contact us.
